[
  {
    "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "High Text Machine Language",
      "Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language",
      "Home Tool Markup Language"
    ],
    "answer": "Hyper Text Markup Language"
  },
  {
    "question": "HTML is called a markup language because:",
    "options": [
      "It contains loops and conditions",
      "It marks content using tags",
      "It compiles into machine code",
      "It runs on the server"
    ],
    "answer": "It marks content using tags"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of HTML?",
    "options": [
      "To style web pages",
      "To create and structure web page content",
      "To perform Validatios.",
      "To execute server-side logic"
    ],
    "answer": "To create and structure web page content"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main difference between p tag and pre tags in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "<p> preserves spaces, <pre> removes them",
      "<p> collapses extra spaces and line breaks, <pre> preserves them exactly",
      "<p> is semantic, <pre> is non-semantic",
      "<p> is inline, <pre> is block-level"
    ],
    "answer": "<p> collapses extra spaces and line breaks, <pre> preserves them exactly"
  },
  {
    "question": "When should an ordered list be used?",
    "options": [
      "When order does not matter",
      "When sequence is important",
      "When data is tabular",
      "When adding links"
    ],
    "answer": "When sequence is important"
  },
  {
    "question": "When should an unordered list be used?",
    "options": [
      "When order does not matter",
      "When sequence is important",
      "When data is tabular",
      "When adding links"
    ],
    "answer": "When order does not matter"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of lists in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "Styling content",
      "Organizing related information",
      "Creating tables",
      "Adding images"
    ],
    "answer": "Organizing related information"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are tables used in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "To design page layout",
      "To display structured data in rows and columns",
      "To style content",
      "To create forms"
    ],
    "answer": "To display structured data in rows and columns"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a table with 5 rows and 4 columns. How many  td tags are needed if no cell merges are used?",
    "options": [
      "5",
      "4",
      "20",
      "19"
    ],
    "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which character encoding supports multiple languages, symbols, and emojis?",
    "options": [
      "ASCII",
      "ISO-8859-1",
      "UTF-8",
      "ANSI"
    ],
    "answer": "UTF-8"
  },
  {
    "question": "If we need to get the details of a single employee, what should we select?",
    "options": [
      "Table Data",
      "Column Data",
      "Row Data",
      "Cell Data"
    ],
    "answer": "Row Data"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct about rowspan in an HTML table?",
    "options": [
      "It is used to merge multiple columns",
      "It is used to merge multiple rows",
      "It defines table headers",
      "It increases table width"
    ],
    "answer": "It is used to merge multiple rows"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of HTML forms?",
    "options": [
      "To display images",
      "To collect user input",
      "To format text",
      "To play videos"
    ],
    "answer": "To collect user input"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which input type allows selecting only ONE option from multiple choices?",
    "options": [
      "checkbox",
      "textbox",
      "Radio Button",
      "List"
    ],
    "answer": "Radio Button"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which button submits the form by default?",
    "options": [
      "<button type=\"button\">",
      "<button type=\"submit\">",
      "<input type=\"reset\">",
      "<input type=\"text\">"
    ],
    "answer": "<button type=\"submit\">"
  },
  {
    "question": "Multiple checkboxes share the same name. What happens?",
    "options": [
      "Only one value is sent",
      "Last value is sent",
      "All selected values are sent as a list",
      "Form fails"
    ],
    "answer": "All selected values are sent as a list"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the reset button do?",
    "options": [
      "Submits data",
      "Reloads page",
      "Clears all form inputs to default values",
      "Deletes form"
    ],
    "answer": "Clears all form inputs to default values"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are semantic elements important in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "They reduce page size",
      "They improve code readability, accessibility, and SEO",
      "They replace CSS",
      "They execute JavaScript"
    ],
    "answer": "They improve code readability, accessibility, and SEO"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of the anchor (a) tag in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "To display images",
      "To create hyperlinks for navigation between pages",
      "To format text",
      "To group elements"
    ],
    "answer": "To create hyperlinks for navigation between pages"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of HTML Entities?",
    "options": [
      "To style HTML elements",
      "To represent reserved or special characters in HTML",
      "To create hyperlinks",
      "To group HTML elements"
    ],
    "answer": "To represent reserved or special characters in HTML"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Not correct about div tag in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "The main div can have sub divisions.",
      "To create Multiple hyperlinks.",
      "To group elements for layout and styling purposes.",
      "It is a Block level Element."
    ],
    "answer": "To create Multiple hyperlinks."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the not correct about DOM?",
    "options": [
      "DOM stands for Document Object Model",
      "Tree of objects of HTML elements",
      "DOM created by Browser when the page loaded",
      "Used to load load images"
    ],
    "answer": "Used to load load images"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a semantic element in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "<main>",
      "<article>",
      "<details>",
      "<summary>",
      "<div>"
    ],
    "answer": "<div>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about comments in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "Comments are not displayed in the browser.",
      "Comments help developers understand the code.",
      "Comments can contain HTML tags that get executed by the browser.",
      "Comments are ignored by the browser."
    ],
    "answer": "Comments can contain HTML tags that get executed by the browser."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which HTML element should appear only once per page?",
    "options": [
      "<section>",
      "<article>",
      "<main>",
      "<aside>"
    ],
    "answer": "<main>"
  }
]